

# SERCAN ÇELENK

**EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

ISTANBUL / TURKEY · [+90 530 200 85 02] · SERCANCELENK@GMAIL.COM



"Passionate about IT Profession and Computer Engineering. Have years of experience on Software Development. Designed and building several Softwares with Java, Scala, Ruby, Python. Both had experience in Startups and Enterprise Scale organizations."









# **EXPERIENCE**

## **EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY

Fizy Music Platform, Magazine Platform, Online Gaming Platform, TV+ Middleware

04/2016 - Present

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

GLOBAL CAPITAL GROUP ONLINE BANKING COMPANY

Project based working in Payment Team.

10/2015 - 04/2016

## **HEAD OF CORE DEVELOPMENT**

**DUMETECH** 

Dumetech is startup company of us. We developed Mesaj.Ninja Project that online messaging platform via Whatsapp, Viber, Bip. Also we acquire reward from BNP Pariba International Hackhaton in Istanbul.

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY

Eclipse Plugin and Middleware development for Release Management in Turkcell.

10/2013 - 01/2015

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

AKBANK TECHNOLOGY

Main Banking Team, development of financial applications.

04/2012 - 11/2013

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

**EG SOFTWARE COMPANY** 

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

05/2010 - 04/2012

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

MAG SOFTWARE COMPANY

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

04/2008 - 05/2010

# **PROJECTS**

## **ONLINE GAMING PLATFORM**

Core backend development

Reactive Programming with Java 1.8 and projectreactor.io.

Reactive Manifesto, Monads, Functional Programming

Reactive Apache Kafka Cluster Pub/Sub Messaging and Reactive Websocket

250000+ connections in one machine on T instant

Reactive Redis Template, Google Guava Memoizer for in-memory cache

Spring 5 Webflux

### **FIZY MUSIC PLATFORM**

Online Music Streaming Platform

Core Development

Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8 Functional

Redis Cluster, Redis Sentinel

Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter

Java Concurrency for music content data polling

Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

Turkcell Technology

## **MAGAZINE PLATFORM**

Online Magazine Platform

Replatform Project from .NET to Java Microservice

Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8 Functional

Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache

Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter

Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

Turkcell Technology

#### TV+ CHAT MODULE

Reactive Apache Kafka Messaging, Reactive Websocket, Reactive Redis, Spring 5.x, Reactive Programming Spring 5 Webflux

Mockito JUnit

Turkcell Technology

## **GOLLER CEPTE MIDDLEWARE**

Reactive Apache Kafka Messaging for realtime match details, Reactive Websocket, Reactive Redis, Spring 5.x,

Reactive Programming

Spring 5 Webflux

Mockito JUnit

Turkcell Technology

## **PAYMENT MODULE**

Spring Boot 1.5, Microservice Architecture, ELK, Zepplin, Zuul Filter, Mockito JUnit

Global Capital Group

## **FLEXDQ - DATA QUALITY TOOL FOR INTEGRATED SYSTEMS**

Spring boot 1.5, Java 1.8, Spring Data, Mysql DB

Spring Quartz Dynamic Job Scheduling

Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache

Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

Turkcell Technology

## DEVELOPER OF SDLC FOR CI / CD AND RELEASE MANAGEMENT PROCESSES

Java 1.7, Spring Data, J2EE, Eclipse Plugin Development, Rest Api Developed the following modules: Web Api, Schedule Api, Rest Api, Log monitoring Api Integration of Clearcase and SVN

Eclipse Plugin Development, SWT adapted, Threaded GUI

Turkcell Technology

### HAZZMON-IO

Hazelcast Key and Cluster Management Tool Manage your hazelcast on-demand for your project. Easy setup. Github: https://github.com/sercancelenk/hazzmon-io Spring Boot 2.x, Hazelcast Supported All Versions, AngularJs 6 for UI

Turkcell Technology

## MESAJ.NINJA - CLOUD MESSAGING APPLICATION VIA WHATSAPP, VIBER

TEB BNP Paribas Hackathon Winner Project Spring Technologies, Java 1.8, Java concurrency, Ruby Cucumber Integration, AngularJs Dumetech

## **GUNDEM.IN INTELLIGENCE NEWS CRAWLER APPLICATION**

From 200+ resources, crawl and serve news data on mobile phone, Mix news with twitter and facebook Apache Kafka for crawling data on demand, Ruby Sinatra Framework, Solr for indexing and grouping news Personal

## **SKILLS**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS































- Reactive Programming, Reactive Manifesto, Scalable Systems
- Java 1.6, 1.7, 1.8, Functional Programming, Design Patterns experience (Advanced)
- Dockerize Applications, CI/CD, Jenkins Integrated Applications
- Scala for multithreaded processing with functional
- Clean code, Microservices Architectures

- Spring Rest Docs, Mockito, JUnit
- Spring Data, Rest, Webflux, Oauth, Hibernate, JWT (Advanced)
- Scala for multithreaded processing with functional
- Apache Kafka Messaging (Pub/Sub)
- Redis Sentinel, Redis Server Cluster, Sharding
- Hazelcast Cluster, Google Guava, Ehcache
- Ruby (Intermediate) Sinatra, Rails Frameworks

#### **WORKFIOW**

Accept and Analyze Problem Find most suitable solution Develop most efficiently Agile Development & Scrum

# **AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS**

(Mesaj.Ninja Project) BNP Paribas & TEB International Hackhaton Winner in ISTANBUL (2015)

Oracle OCA Certificate (2011) (Oracle-Ireland)

Java 1.8 New fetures (2015) (Oracle)

Java EE (2013-2014) - Oracle

Spring Framework Architecture (2013) (kodcu.com)

JavaSE and Design Patterns (2007) (Oracle)





# **GIVEN LECTURES**

Startup Roadmap (I.T.U Cekirdek)

Reactive Programming (Turkcell Technology)

Java 1.8 New features (Turkcell Technology)

Sql Tuning (Bilge Adam)

# **EDUCATION**

## **SELÇUK UNIVERSITY**

ENGINEERING FACULTY - COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT

Graduated.

# **INTERESTS**

- In my free time I like playing guitar, playing football, driving a car, and reading politics.
- Professionally, I like to constantly develop myself, create other fields, learn other languages, produce new ideas and projects.

# **REFERENCES**

• References will be supplied in case of request.